大家好
Hello,
我是谢尔顿·库珀博士
I'm Dr. Sheldon Cooper,
欢迎收看由谢尔顿·库珀出品的
and welcome to the premiere episode
《有趣的旗帜》之首播集
of Sheldon Cooper Presents: Fun with Flags.
在接下来的五十二周  我们将一起探索
Over the next 52 weeks, you and I are going to explore
旗帜学的奇妙世界
the dynamic world of vexillology.
等一下  库博士
Hang on, Dr. C.
旗帜学是什么
What's vexillology?
旗帜学就是研究旗帜的
Vexillology is the study of flags.
真棒
Cool.
我想我又长见识了
I think I just learned something.
-你觉得有趣吗  -当然
- Did you have fun doing it? - I'll say.
这个节目具有两面性  趣味性和知识性
Fun and information are two sides to this video podcast,
就如同这面两面的州旗
not unlike the only two-sided state flag--
一面是俄勒冈洲
Oregon.
瞧
Oh, look.
俄勒冈州该州以喜栖息于水边挖穴而居的海狸作为象征
故有海狸州的别称
你好  海狸先生
Hello, Mr. Beaver.
在接下来的节目里  我们会回答一些热门问题
In future episodes, we'll answer some burning questions:
唯一一面不是长方形的旗帜是什么
What's the only non-rectangular flag?
在旗帜上出现最多的动物是什么
What animal appears most often on flags?
在旗帜上出现第二多的动物是什么
What animal appears second most often on flags?
等等
And more.
太棒了
Sweet!
你为什么挥白旗
Why are you waving a white flag?
因为太欢乐了
I'm surrendering...
我投降了
to fun.
今天《有趣的旗帜》的内容并不有趣
Now, today's episode of Fun with Flags is not fun,
但十分重要
but it is important.
旗帜第一课  要学会如何拿
"Flags: you gotta know how to hold 'em,
如何叠
you gotta know how to fold 'em."
那我们先开始认识旗帜的结构
Let's start by identifying the parts of our flag.
这边是吊孔  用来...
This edge is the hoist, and it's used to...
抱歉  借过一下
Excuse me, sorry, excuse me.
停
Cut.
你没看到我们在拍吗
Did you not see we are rolling?
抱歉  我要和佩妮一起吃晚饭
Sorry. I'm having dinner with Penny.
我得赶紧出门
I have to get out of here.
而我满脑子的旗帜知识
And I have flag knowledge
我也得让它们赶紧出来
that I have to get out of here!
你没事吧
You okay?
没事  就是有点生气
No, I'm a little rattled.
美国南北战争在萨姆特要塞打响
但就像萨姆特要塞的旗帜  我还坚守着呢
But like the flag over Fort Sumter, I'm still here.
第二遍
And... take two.
大家好
Hello.
我是谢尔顿·库珀博士
I'm Dr. Sheldon Cooper,
欢迎收看由谢尔顿·库珀出品的
and welcome to the premiere episode
《有趣的旗帜》之首播集
of Sheldon Cooper Presents: Fun with Flags.
在接下来的五十二周  我们将一起探索
Over the next 52 weeks, you and I are going to explore
旗帜学的奇妙世界
the dynamic world of vexillology.
等一下  库珀博士
Hang on, Dr. Cooper.
旗帜学是什么
What's vexillology?
旗帜学就是...
Vexillology is...
为什么旗帜上有张脸
Why is there a face on that flag?
他叫斐迪南·T·旗帜
It's Ferdinand T. Flag.
我觉得他能吸引少儿观众群
I thought he might help bring in some younger viewers.
真讨厌  不过没错  这主意妙
Confound it! You're right, it's brilliant.
我们从头开始录吧
Let's take it from the top.
生活大爆炸第五季第十四集
晚饭真不错
That was a really nice dinner.
我很开心你又约我出去了
I'm glad you asked me out again.
我也是  我很想你
Me, too; I missed you.
你天天都能看到我
You see me all the time.
你确定你想的不是滚床单的部分吗
You sure you just don't miss the sex?
好吧  和你滚床单的感觉是很棒
Well, yeah, sex with you is pretty great.
你试过吗
Have you ever tried it?
试过  你说的没错
I have. You are not wrong.
我只是觉得  如果我们要复合的话
I just think if we're gonna try dating again,
应该慢慢来
we should take things slow.
我可以慢慢来啊
Oh, I can take it slow.
我有和你说过我高中时的第一任女友
Did I ever tell you about my first girlfriend in high school,
凯伦·波布瑞克吗
Karen Berberick?
至今她都不知道当时我们是在约会
To this day she doesn't know we were going out.
不过这么一来  分手的时候就容易多了
Made it easier on her when I broke things off.
好吧  也不要那么慢
Okay, well, maybe not that slow.
那这样吧
How about this,
你知道电脑软件通常是怎么开发的吗
are you familiar with the typical development for computer software?
为了好玩  就当我不知道好了
You know, just for fun, let's say I'm not.
在一款应用程序发布之前
Before an application is released,
都会先进行测试
they give it a trial run.
我们可以这么做
W-We could do that.
如果我们遇到分歧  不要生气
And if we hit a rough spot, instead of getting mad,
就当是发现了个问题
just say, "Hey, we found a bug,"
把问题报告出来  然后修复
and we report it so it can be fixed.
是像公开测试那种吗
You mean like a beta test?
严格上来说  这是内部测试
Well, technically, this would be an alpha test.
公开测试是给没参与
A beta test requires people that weren't involved
程序开发的无关人士...
in the development of the appli...
我好歹知道"公开测试"  不该表扬一下吗
Seriously, do I not get credit for knowing beta test?
当然
No, you should.
当然了  是我在卖弄学问
Absolutely. That was me being pedantic.
这是我们的第一个问题
That's our first bug.
你报告了
You reported it.
我修复了
I can fix that.
看见吗  这样不错
See? This is good.
好吧  那我们就试试
All right. Let's give it a shot.
很好  咱俩都列个单子记录
Great. You keep a list, I'll keep a list.
到时候再交换
At some point, we'll exchange.
好
Okay.
-晚安  莱纳德  -晚安
- Good night, Leonard. - Night.
干得好  霍夫斯塔德
Attaboy, Hofstadter.
没什么比喻能比软件开发
Nothing gets the ladies hotter
更能让女人兴奋
than software development analogies.
我回来了
Hey, I'm back.
停
Cut.
第四十七遍
Take 47.
告诉你一件旗帜的趣事
Here's an interesting fact about flags.
我就当你自动开录了
I will take that action.
列支敦斯登和海地的国旗
The flags of Liechtenstein and Haiti
以前碰巧是一样的
were identical by coincidence,
直到两国在1936年奥运会对战时
a fact that wasn't discovered until they competed
才发现这个巧合
against each other at the 1936 Olympics.
不过幸好  当时西班牙内战拯救了
And thankfully,their embarrassment was overshadowed
1936年西班牙人民开始反法西斯斗争
其内战被称为"小二战"
让两国的尴尬
by the rise of Fascism.
看看你的新手机
Let's see the new phone.
我在上班路上买的
I stopped on the way to work.
你要不要跟我一起揭开贴膜
Hey, do you want to peel the plastic off with me?
我何德何能呀
Really? Me?
这可是最棒那部分呀
That's, like, the best part.
从边上揭吧
Grab a corner.
喂  别这么猴急  粗鲁牛仔
Whoa, what's your hurry, cowboy?
享受这一刻
Savor the moment.
太他妈爽了
Oh, yeah.
说到牛仔
Speaking of cowboys,
知道哪个国家的国旗印着两只牛吗
do you know what country has not one but two cows on its flag?
内陆小国家  安道尔共和国
The tiny landlocked nation of Andorra.
由谢尔顿·库珀出品的
Oh, the next classic episode
《旗帜的乐趣》  精彩下一集
of Sheldon Cooper Presents: Fun with Flags
题材如泉涌呀
is writing itself.
让我试试语音识别功能
Oh, let me try the voice recognition.
去  人家都让你揭膜了  别得寸进尺
Hey, I let you peel the plastic, don't get greedy.
你好
Hello?
Hello.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
我的名字叫Siri
My name? It's Siri.
瞧瞧
Look at that.
终于出现一个你敢跟她讲话的女人了
There's finally a woman in your life you can talk to.
你现在是单身吗
Are you single?
如果你是问婚姻状况的话
I don't have a marital status,
我没有这个属性
if that's what you're asking.
也是  这个问题太私人了
Yeah, you're right, that's too personal.
我们才刚认识
We hardly know each other.
去喝杯咖啡怎么样
How about a cup of coffee?
我找到六个咖啡馆
I've found six coffee shops.
其中三个离你很近
Three of them are fairly close to you.
先生们回见啦
I will see you gentlemen later.
她铁定让他心碎
She is gonna break his heart.
对于利用时光机
For someone who has a machine
穿越时空的人
that can travel anywhere in time and space,
《神秘博士》  英国科幻电视剧
神秘博士对现代的伦敦还真是情有独钟
Doctor Who sure does have a thing for modern-day London.
注意点  说这种无礼的话
Careful, it's that kind of sass
会让你被今年神秘会谈的拒之门外
that can get a person uninvited to this year's Who Con.
我们这次不算约会吧
Uh, we're not counting this as a date, are we?
我不确定
Um, I'm not sure,
不过我觉得正确答案应该是"不算"
but I think the right answer here is "no."
问题报告  当异性约我出来
Bug report: When a guy asks me to spend time with him,
他是不是应该安排一些更有趣的事
maybe he plans something a little more interesting
而不是坐在家里看电视
than hanging out at home, watching TV.
《神秘博士》也没趣?
Even Doctor Who?
《神秘博士》很没趣
Even Doctor Who.
够了  神秘会谈没你份
All right, that's it. Who Con-- you're out.
好的  问题报告已收到
Okay, bug report taken.
下次我会安排更好的夜晚活动
Next time I will have a better plan for our evening's activity.
谢谢  明天见
Well, thank you. I'll see you tomorrow.
等等  我差点忘了
Oh, wait, here, almost forgot.
-给  -这是什么
- Here. - What's this?
我记录你的问题报告
My bug report to you.
这表列得还挺长的嘛
Well, that's quite a list you got there.
有分颜色标记
It's color coded.
红色的代表"马上修复"
Uh, red means "fix right away."
黄色的代表"有时间再说"
Yellow is "eh, whenever you get a chance."
绿色的代表"我应该可以适应"
And green, is "I could probably learn to live with it."
最下面还有标注呢
There's a key down here at the bottom.
一目了然吧
It's neat, huh?
是
Yep.
那晚安啦
So, have a good night.
好
Yep.
瞧瞧
Look at that.
将来我们可以告诉后人
Some day, we will tell future generations
约会变得不再困难
that dating used to be hard.
我不解的是你能列出什么问题
What's baffling me is what you could've possibly put on the list.
"秀发太金黄"?
"Hair too golden"?
"笑声太动听"?
"Laugh too musical"?
"她的出现"
"World too much a better place
"让世界更美好"?
for her mere presence in it"?
"经常说话的时候满嘴食物"  这条怎么样
How about "constantly talks with food in her mouth"?
她内心充满爱  没人会在意她嘴里有什么
Her heart's full of love, no one cares what's in her mouth.
Siri
So, Siri,
怎么样  你最近好吗
what's happening? How are you?
我很好
I am well.
你现在在干什么
What are you doing right now?
你还能在干什么
What am I doing?
我在跟你说话啊
I'm talking with you.
你的声音真好听
You have a beautiful voice.
谢谢  有人欣赏很真好
Thank you, it's nice to be appreciated.
这是自然
I bet it is.
为什么没有女人喜欢我
Why don't women like me?
我查查看
Let me check on that.
网页搜索下"为什么没有女人喜欢我"怎么样
How about a Web search for "Why don't women like me?"
不用了  我早就搜过了
No need. I've already done that.
Siri  你有姓吗
Siri, do you have a last name?
我名叫Siri
My name is Siri.
只有名啊
Ah, one name.
像雪儿  麦当娜 阿黛尔
Like, uh, Cher, Madonna, Adele.
她们的声音都让我荡漾
All the women who rock me.
我名叫拉杰什  但你可以叫我拉杰
My name is Rajesh, but you can call me Raj.
你想要我叫你拉杰吗
Would you like me to call you Raj?
我想要你叫我帅哥
I'd like you to call me sexy.
从现在起  我叫你帅哥  好吗
From now on, I'll call you sexy. Okay?
好啊
Okay!
Siri  我想吃意大利冰激凌
Siri, I'm in the mood for gelato.
我找到了十家评论里有意大利冰激凌的餐厅
I found ten restaurants whose reviews mention gelato.
其中七家离你相当近
Seven of them are fairly close to you.
谢谢  亲爱的
Thank you, darling.
你太客气了  帅哥
You are most certainly welcome, sexy.
不错嘛  库萨帕里教授
Well done, Dr. Koothrappali.
怎么了
I'm sorry?
你迈出了革命性的一步
You've taken a great evolutionary leap
你放弃了和人类的互动
by abandoning human interaction and allowing yourself
却爱上了和冷冰冰的机器打情骂俏
to romantically bond with a soulless machine.
Kudos  一款虚拟人生游戏的名字
赞一个
Kudos.
我没爱上它
I haven't bonded with it.
是的  那当然
Oh, no, of course.
我懂得
I understand.
你害怕这世界还不能接受你的禁忌之爱
You're afraid the world isn't ready for your taboo love.
我会守口如瓶的
Your secret's safe with me.
这只是个手机
It's just a phone.
库珀
Cooper.
克莱皮克
Kripke.
通报
Heads up.
克莱皮克把所有l和r的音发成了w
莱曼教授又在粒子物理实验"司"撒尿了
Professor Rothman urinated in the particle physics wab again,
我们要把他的"腿休"派对提前
so we're going to move up his wetirement party.
星"基"五  五点  自带"饲"品
Fwiday, 5:00-- pot wuck.
谢谢  巴里
Thanks, Barry.
Siri  星期五早上提醒我
Siri, remind me Friday morning
制做我拿手的印度飞饼
to make my famous popovers.
好的  我会提醒你
All right, I'll remind you.
你用Siwi  对吧
You got Siwi, huh?
语音"私"别系统真是"罩"透了
Voice wecognition on that thing is tewwible.
"侃"
Wook.
Siwi  你能"腿"荐个"番"馆吗
Siwi, can you wecommend a westauwant?
对不起  巴尼[里]
I'm sorry, Bawwy.
我不懂什么是"腿荐个番馆"
I don't understand "wecommend a westauwant."
"钉"我说
Wisten to me.
不是"番"馆  是"番"馆
Not westauwant; westauwant.
我不明白什么是
I don't know what you mean
"不是番馆  是番馆"
by "not westauwant; westauwant."
瞧  "肥"物一个
See? Total cwap.
Siwi  你烂死了
You suck, Siwi.
嘿  不要跟她这么说
Hey, don't talk to her like that.
她是位女士
She's a lady.
"作"晚  这位"奴"士给我的老二
Well, that wady took high-wes pictures
拍高"擎"的照片  并发到广告"性"息网
of my junk wast night for Cwaigswist.
"挥"头见
Waiter.
门没关
It's open.
你准备走了吗
You ready to go?
等等  让我把这章看完
Yeah, hang on. Let me just finish this chapter.
你不能晚点看吗
Can you finish it later?
不行
No, I can't.
看书现在是我生活中重要的一部分  因为...
Reading books is a big part of my life now because, you know,
我看得越多  我们的共同话题就越多
we'd have more fun things to talk about if I read more.
太好了  太好了
Great. Good. Great.
你在看什么
What are you reading?
两星期腹肌速成
Two Weeks to Rock Hard Abs.
光书名就剧透了  不是吗
They kind of spoil the ending right in the name of that, don't they?
好的
All right.
听着  要记住我们的约定
Look, just remember how this works.
不能因为这些事情生气
We don't get mad about these things.
说到这  我根据你的问题报告
Uh, speaking of which, I've addressed
修正了我今晚的约会安排
your bug report on my date planning.
今晚的节目很有意思
Got a really fun evening for you.
算是个惊喜吧
It's kind of a surprise.
好的  很好
All right. Terrific.
那让我找双不那么高的鞋子
Well, let me just go find a pair of shoes that aren't so tall.
这样你就不会觉得
We wouldn't want you to feel like you were
是在跟自己的妈妈散步
out for a walk with your mommy.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是我给你的报告  放这儿了
Here's my list for you-- right there.
好的  有来有往
All right, fair enough.
接吻的时候  我当然能安静点
I certainly can be quieter when we kiss.
我原以为这是热情的表示
I thought it was an expression of passion,
但是如果被形容为"很湿很奇怪"
but if it's coming across as "juicy and weird,"
我宁愿作罢
who wants that?
不好意思
Uh, uh... I'm sorry.
你能解释下  我的眉毛"很笨"是什么是意思
Can you be more specific on how my eyebrows are "stupid"?
不用了  看见了
No, never mind. It's right here.
来得正好
Good timing.
饭菜都快准备好了
Dinner's almost ready.
太好了
Great.
闻起来很不错
Oh, smells amazing in here.
我们吃什么
Oh, what are we eating?
来点异域风情
Oh, an exotic little treat.
我正在跟Siri谈北京烤鸭
I was just talking to Siri about Peking duck,
她说她知道四家中国食品店
and she said she knew about four Chinese grocers,
其中两家离这很近
two of which were fairly close to me.
我被她自发性的语音功能传染了
Her spontaneity is contagious.
Siri是谁啊
Who's Siri?
他有新女友了吗
Is he dating somebody new?
是啊  他手机嘛
Yes. His phone.
这该算是可爱还是可怕啊
Is that cute or creepy?
我给你们倒点酒吧
Can I pour you some wine?
你们会喜欢的
I think you'll enjoy it.
一般来说  北京烤鸭是佐以
The traditional choice with Peking duck
长相思葡萄酒而食
is a sauvignon blanc,
另译白苏维翁  一种果香丰富的白葡萄酒
但Siri建议我采用非干型威士莲佐餐
but Siri suggested an off-dry Riesling.
非干型:形容葡萄酒有一些甜味 但不是很甜
威士莲:最精致的白葡萄酒品种
我也不确定
I wasn't sure,
但我实在不想
but I didn't want to have an argument
在乔氏超市连锁店跟她吵起来
with her in the middle of Trader Joe's.
该让Siri穿什么衣服赴宴呢
Now, what should we put Siri in for dinner?
性感的豹纹壳  闪耀的钻石壳
Leopard, sparkles,
可可·香奈儿  20世纪法国设计师
或者用可可·香奈儿的话来说
or to paraphrase Coco Chanel,
黑色是永不出错的颜色
you can never go wrong with a little black case?
Siri  为我们奏一曲抒情爵士乐吧
Siri, play some smooth jazz.
播放抒情爵士乐
Playing smooth jazz.
凯丽·金  全球最著名的高音萨克斯风名家
天啊  是凯丽·金的曲子
Oh, my God, Kenny G?!
这个女人简直把我看透了
This woman can read me like a book.
我不敢相信居然在格兰岱尔凯丹广场  买到了我的灵魂伴侣
I can't believe I bought my soul mate at Glendale Galleria.
我觉得我待不下去了
I don't know if I want to stay.
这简直酷毙了
This is amazing.
你是怎么想到这主意的
How did you even get this idea
我打电话给你爸
I called your dad.
问他你小时候都爱玩些什么
I asked him what things you liked to do when you were a kid.
来这里比找头牛让你玩推到
This seemed easier than getting a cow out here
容易多了
so you could tip it.
你真是棒极了
Okay, you're kind of really great.
你是在夸一个按摩你脖子时
You mean for a person whose neck massages feel like
就像老鹰要把你叼回巢里的人吗
an eagle is trying to carry you to its nest?
问题报告
Okay, bug report.
我刚夸奖了你
I just complimented you.
你应该欣然接受  然后闭嘴
You should take it and shut up.
好  我错了  对不起
Right. Sorry, sorry.
不要没完没了地向我道歉
And stop apologizing all the time.
好  对不起
Right. Sorry.
好啦  咱们开练吧
All right, let's shoot stuff.
需要我教你怎样射击吗
You want me to show you what to do?
我可是个玩《侠盗猎车手》的老手
I play a lot of Grand Theft Auto.
玩起手枪可是驾轻就熟
I think I know how to handle a gat.
你痞里痞气的时候还真可爱
Wow. You are cute when you get all gangsta.
现在我多了处枪伤
So, I've got a gunshot wound.
痞子感更十足了吧
That's pretty bad-ass.
才不是呢  是你的锐步鞋上多了处枪伤
No, you've got a Reebok with a gunshot wound
你那粉嫩的脚趾头不过是擦伤
and an ouchie on your pinky toe.
拜托  医生给我贴了个创可贴
Hello? They gave me a Band-aid.
医院不能随便给病人开创可贴的
Hospitals do not issue Band-aids
除非是伤情严重  万不得已
unless it is medically necessary.
这可是法律规定
That is the law.
今晚酷毙了  谢谢你
Well, thank you for a really cool evening.
也谢谢你在急诊室帮我
Thank you for hiding my Star Wars socks
把《星球大战》的袜子藏起来
at the emergency room.
现在我们是不是评估下公测
Is it a good time to evaluate the beta test
看看我们的进展了
and see where we stand?
前途一片光明
Things are looking good.
那么  我们还要慢慢来吗
So, are we still taking things slow?
鉴于今天我受了枪伤
Because a gunshot wound today,
而上周
and last week,
我的大拇指被厨房的抽屉给夹伤
I slammed my thumb in the kitchen drawer.
我估计我命不久矣
We don't know how much time I have.
晚安
Good night, you.
以下为德语
YouTube上的各位看官  您好
Guten Tag, das YouTube.
我是巴伐利亚人
Ich bin ein Bavarian.
椒盐脆饼  巴伐利亚传统小吃
而我是椒盐脆饼
Und ich bin eine pretzel!
谢尔顿·库珀倾情奉献
Und dis is Sheldon Cooper Presents:
《有趣的旗帜》
Fun...Mit...Flags.
左手边第一个门
First door on the left.
谢谢
Thank you.
Siri的办公室
戴夫  我在你家附近找到六家吸尘器维修店
Dave, I found six vacuum cleaner repair shops in your area.
其中有4个离你家非常近
Four are fairly close to you.
你好  帅哥
Hello, sexy.
有什么需要我效劳
What can I help you with?
如果你想跟我滚床单  只管告诉我就好
If you'd like to make love to me, just tell me.
对不起  我不知道什么是...
I'm sorry. I don't understand...
不要啊
No!